David Baladi

FRONT END DEVELOPER ✓ HTML/CSS/JavaScript ✓ Sass/TypeScript/React ✓ Node/Express/Fetch/Axios/GCP ✓ Python/Java/C/C++/C# ✓ MySQL/Kaggle/Pramp ✓ SSMS/Access/Power Query Editor

Dear Hiring Manager,

With my React front end developer and professional contractor experience, I am able to wear different hats and be a developer, project manager, modeler and chief communicator of solutions. I am highly active at adopting business-specific practices upon entering new roles. I also possess strong knowledge of project life cycle operations and workflow management strategies. Feel free to review the following relevant points.

Relevant Experience:

1) I currently work on a software development team to build web and mobile CRM applications with React, React Native, TypeScript, Redux and Axios.

Result: Quickly integrated within development teams to consistently provide client deliverables on time.

2) I do independent contract work for professional business websites where I am required to articulate high-technical knowledge to non-technical individuals.

Result: Improved business visibility (SEO ranking) and user experience of www.torontoguitarschool.com and www.mintmusic.ca.

3) I have constructed a diverse portfolio of React projects that implement Node, Express, Axios and other technologies.

Result: Completed personal portfolio website \$\alpha\$ and conducted extensive documentation research.

- 4) As Reporting Owner, I researched and consolidated program scheduling and cost data for the Darlington Nuclear Generating Station Refurbishment \$12 Billion government program. Employed government level Enterprise Project Controls workflow management and communication strategies to lead projects independently and meet deliverables for Executive review and publication.
 - **Result:** Increased transparency of program inefficiencies and facilitated millions in savings, with one-on-one monthly reviews with Senior Management for publications.
- 5) I cut project complexity and cost by programming a TCP connection to enable wireless streaming of Raspberry Pi video footage for Windows machine learning processing.

Result: Successfully integrated remote object detection and facial recognition into a robot assistant design and configured seamless tracking of detection results by robot motors, in addition to gaining proficiency in Python, C++, Stack Overflow, Linux/Windows terminal and socket programming.

I encourage you to review the attached resume for additional details regarding my qualification. Thank you for your consideration.

Sincerely,

David Baladi, B.Eng.

David Baladi

Front End Developer_

I am a React developer who likes to rely on first principles as well as experiment with innovative approaches to technology and efficiency challenges. My questioning growth mindset enables me to quickly absorb strong project knowledge and establish my impact to project teams.

Technical Skills

Developer: HTML · CSS · JavaScript · Git · React · Redux · TypeScript · Sass · Axios · Node · Express · GCP

Additional: Python · C · Java · MySQL · MATLAB · SSMS · Excel Power Query · Access · Kaggle · Pramp

Experience

Front End Developer · ConsulNet Computing Inc., Toronto, ON · Jan 2022 - Present

Utilized front end stack (React, TypeScript, Redux, Axios) to build commercial CRM applications:

- Worked with Axios access tokens and Open Authorization to manage user logins.
- Developed reusable components that communicate to company RESTful API (.NET framework, C#).
- Software consulting and project issue tracking with Azure DevOps boards.

React Developer · Freelance, Toronto, ON · Jun 2020 - Present

Developing, redirecting, and maintaining professional business websites:

- Improved user experience and Google Search ranking of www.mintmusic.ca by one-on-one prototyping with the business owner, demonstrating modern UX designs and SEO strategies.
- Tracked and planned spirits with Jira, adhering to Agile and Scrum methodologies.

Project Controls Specialist · Ontario Power Generation, Darlington, ON · May 2020 - Dec 2021

Reporting owner on the Darlington Nuclear Generating Station Refurbishment \$12 Billion government program:

- Enforced cross-department collaboration via project management tools to adopt project-wide knowledge to ensure comprehensive deliverables were completed on plan without risk to data integrity for Senior Management review and publication.
- Improved program schedule and cost transparency through deep dive SSMS and Excel Power Query analytics.

Python Programmer · *Toronto Metropolitan University, Toronto, ON* · *Aug 2019 - Apr 2020* Integrated object retrieval algorithms into personal robot assistant:

- Programmed a microcomputer (Raspberry Pi) to wirelessly stream video frames to a Windows laptop across a TCP network connection for autonomous fetch and return algorithms (object detection and facial recognition).

Projects

Feel free to visit my personal website & demonstrating below diverse project portfolio:

- 1) CRUD application that utilizes Node and Express to store and send to-do list items
- 2) Robotic integration of YOLOv3 object detection and OpenCV facial recognition for object retrieval program
- 3) Google Maps clone that displays regional weather and allows search of restaurants, hotels and attractions \$\begin{align*} & \pi & \hightarrow & \hightarr
- 4) Cryptocurrency application that employs Axios to pull and query recent blockchain data

Education

Toronto Metropolitan University B.Eng. (Computer Software Engineering) 2014 - 2020

Dalhousie University B.Sc. (Neuroscience) 2007 – 2011